# Joshua Schermann

jschermann91@gmail.com | 218-232-7669 | Minneapolis, MN

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:shorturl.at/jktHJ">shorturl.at/jktHJ</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:shorturl.at/nvGV5">shorturl.at/jktHJ</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:shorturl.at/nvGV5">shorturl.at/jktHJ</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:shorturl.at/wxFQS">shorturl.at/wxFQS</a> | Github: <a href="mailto:shorturl.at/nvGV5">shorturl.at/nvGV5</a>

# **Summary**

Full stack web developer with a background in construction. I use my leadership experience, communication skills, and motivated work ethic to succeed in software development. I will complete my MERN Stack Coding Bootcamp on March 23, and I look forward to continuing my personal growth as a developer.

#### Skills

Front End: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Flexbox, Responsive Design

JavaScript: Node.js, jQuery, Handlebars.js, Jest, Mocha, AJAX, React, Object Oriented

Programming

Back End: Express.js, Model View Controller, RESTful APIs, Heroku

Databases: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Object Relational Mapping, Sequelize,

Mongoose

Collaboration: GitHub, GitLab, Agile

### **Projects**

Code Savior GitHub: shorturl.at/fDHW3 Deployment: shorturl.at/nuSXY

- Role: Lead Developer
- Web application for sharing coding resources and taking coding guizzes.
- Users can make and delete posts, upvote posts, and take coding quizzes. I built the quiz functionality and designed back end structure.
- Technologies used: Handlebars.js, Express.js, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, SASS, and Mocha.

Movie Me GitHub: shorturl.at/cxF04 Deployment: shorturl.at/xyJX1

- Role: Lead Developer
- Web application for getting movie recommendations.
- Wikipedia API is used to gather names of over 100 movies in different genres. My role was to build the API fetch requests.
- Technologies used: Open Movie Database API, Wikipedia API, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bulma CSS library

Weather Watch GitHub: <u>shorturl.at/gvISW</u> Deployment: <u>shorturl.at/coOTV</u>

Role: Solo Project

- A web application used for displaying weekly weather information for different cities around the world.
- Client side storage is used for saving city search history.
- Technologies used: Open Weather API, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

### **Work Experience**

**Viet and Co.** Oct 2017 - Jun 2021

Pile Driver Rogers, MN

- Coordinated workflow and motivated team with strict deadlines on massive construction projects.
- Calculated elevations and site layouts, read blueprints, and guided teams.
- Assembled cranes and rigged loads as a Certified Rigger and Signaler.
- Operated pile hammers, drill rigs, forklifts, and aerial lifts.
- Welded structures and shoring systems to engineer's specifications.

Ames Construction Apr 2014 - Oct 2017

Pile Driver Burnsvile, MN

- Built bridges, read blueprints, calculated elevations and performed site layout.
- Communicated workflow with EFCO formwork and concrete pours.
- Assembled cranes and rigged loads as a Certified Rigger and Signaler.
- Operated forklift as Certified Powered Industrial Truck Operator.
- Operated aerial-lift as Certified Aerial Lift Operator.

# **Software Development Student**

July 2021 - Present

Gap explanation

- I resigned from my job in construction to pursue a career in software development. I spent three months studying JavaScript, CSS, and HTML on my own with Codecademy and FreeCodeCamp. In October 2021, I started MERN Stack Coding Bootcamp at the University of Minnesota to continue learning the many technologies needed to become a developer. I will complete my Bootcamp on March 23, 2022.

#### Education

Bachelor's Degree in Design in Architecture at University of Minnesota

MERN Stack Coding Bootcamp at University of Minnesota

March 2022